http://www.linkedin.com/in/andrewyao

### **SUMMARY**

A software engineer with **nine** years of development experience; a passionate, resourceful problem-solver.

## PROGRAMMING SKILLS

• Extensive Experience in

Front End: AJAX, JavaScript, JQuery, CSS, Flex, UI Automation.

Back End: C/C++ (COM, ATL), Java, Oracle Database, SQL, PL/SQL. Test Driven Development.

- Environment: Eclipse, Visual Studio, Linux, Windows, Mac, VMs.
- Working Knowledge in LATEX, Apache, Python, Perl, PHP, MySQL, RESTful architecture.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Principal Member of Technical Staff — Oracle USA, Redwood Shores, CA, 6/2004 - Present

**Technical Lead** in Oracle Support portal, used by millions of Oracle DBAs worldwide. One of the projects was highlighted in **Oracle Open World 2009**, **CEO Larry Ellison's keynote**.

- Modularized and Refactored 300K front-end code into 22 separate, layered libraries.
- Re-architected the front-end into dynamically loadable modules. Reduced initial payload by 40%.
- Improved developer productivity; significantly reduced the client-side compilation time from 3 minutes down to 30 seconds using module techniques; reduced the server-side compilation + deployment + test time from 5+ minutes down to seconds using JUnit.
- Implemented multi-threaded back-end web services, caching, and proxy to external web services.
- Promoted best practices for writing testable code. Improved code coverage from nothing to 60%.
- The 'Go to guy' for Flex, JavaScript, and all other framework related questions.

**Technical Lead** in Monitoring Tools Development. Availability and performance monitoring across multiple geographical locations; used by internal and external customers; one of the larger contracts was in 7 digits. Acting as the architect, designed and developed the following key subsystems:

- A browser-plugin (C++ and JavaScript) that **records**, **analyzes**, and **replays** web transactions.
- The browser-plugin part of a **tracing and diagnostic tool**, which shows the break down of time taken for HTTP requests, Java method calls, and SQLs in an interactive user session.
- Many heuristic techniques that improve the recording accuracy: HTTP traffic and DOM correlation; dynamic variable detection; dynamic Regular Expression generation and substitution.
- Clever event listening techniques that make the recording overhead negligable.
- Parts of a URL fetching tool in C and Java, the key to monitoring availability and performance from multiple geographical locations, without using a real browser.
- Over 30 complex JSP pages for services, web transaction, metrics and thresholds configuration.
- Business model layer, persistence layer using Java, JDBC, SQL and PL/SQL. Tuned the performance of complex back-end SQL queries.

# 701 Baltic Circle, Unit 721 Redwood City, CA 94065, USA

# Andrew Y. Yao andrewyao@gmail.com, (650) 269 8522 http://www.linkedin.com/in/andrewyao

Associate —

Goldman Sachs Inc, New York, NY, 6/2001 - 8/2003

- Consistently ranked in the top quartile in the 360° Annual Review System.
- **Designed** reusable UI components for an in-house AJAX style web application framework.
- Significantly improved the performance of the UI framework and UI components.
- **Developed** a distributed n-tier document search and retrieval system.
- Developed Excel-based financial models, risk analysis models, and staffing management solutions.
- Maintained infrastructure scripts and database schema that manage thousand of desktop machines and servers around the globe.
- The 'Go to guy' for JavaScript, CSS, and Excel questions.

Intern Research Engineer — Canon Information Systems Research, Australia, 12/1998 - 2/2000

- **Researched** two-dimensional image demodulation algorithms, and made a considerable intellectual contribution to the algorithm using spatial and Fourier based methods and MATLAB.
- **Developed** parts of a successful, robust, and reliable scientific image analysis application using C/C++.

## **EDUCATION**

M.S., Computer Science, Full Tuition Scholarship, GPA 3.9 — Cornell University, Ithaca, NY, 2004

- Thesis: Quark A next-generation data management system that searches heterogeneous data source using XQuery. Part of a team that built a functional, end-to-end, open source XQuery engine in C++.
- Database Implementation, Graphics, Distributed Systems, Networks, Scientific Computing

B.S., Computer Engineering, GPA 3.8 - 3.9 — University of New South Wales, Australia, 2000

- First Class Honors, Rank: 2<sup>nd</sup>/111 students, Thesis Scholarship, Canon Academic Excellence Awards
- Thesis: A video annotation and search tool that allows users to annotate (tag) semantic information (keywords) on video clips, and search video clips using the keywords.
- Teaching Assistant: Functional Programming, Algorithms
- Research Assistant: Developed the back-end of an open source search engine CVSSearch using data mining and advanced string matching techniques.
- Published in IEEE International Conference on Software Maintenance (ICSM 2001), Pages 364 373.
- Algorithms, Operating System, OO Design, Database, Computer Architecture, Neural Networks, Image Processing, etc

## OTHER AWARDS

• Member of Australian Mathematics Olympiad National Team Training Squad 1995 & 1996

• Bronze **Medallist** in Asian Pacific Mathematics Olympiad

1996

• Gold Medallist in Australian Mathematics Olympiad

1995 & 1996

• Medallist in Australian Westpac Mathematics Competition

1991 & 1995